Guide to the Asa and Elna Spaulding Papers, 1909-1997 and undated, bulk 1935-1983 RL.01240
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Asa Spaulding Subgroup, 1909-1984 and undated, 331 boxes
  - Correspondence Series, 1935-1983 and undated, 38 boxes
    - Felden, Allie,1958-1962 (Box AC-12)
    - Finch, Robert H.1959-1960 (Box AC-12)
    - Ford, President Gerald R.,1976 (Box AC-12)
    - Foreign Correspondence,1963-1965 (Box AC-12)
    - Frasier, L.B.,1959-1978 (Box AC-12)
    - F,1956-1983, 4 folders (Box AC-12)
    - Galifianakis, Nick,1967-1971 (Box AC-13)
    - Gardner, John W.,1969 (Box AC-13)
    - Gaston, A.G.,1960 (Box AC-13)
    - General Alumni Association,1965 (Box AC-13)
    - General Exchange Insurance Corporation,1937and1940 (Box AC-13)
    - George Washington Carver Memorial Institute,1962 (Box AC-13)
    - German Correspondence,1961-1962, 3 folders (Box AC-13)
    - Germany (Trip toโCorrespondence),1967 (Box AC-13)
    - Goodwill Tour of 1960,1960, 5 folders (Box AC-13)
    - Gilani, Dr. B.S.,1957-1965 (Box AC-14)
    - Godwin, Philip P.,1971 (Box AC-14)
    - Goldberg, Arthur J.,1962 (Box AC-14)
    - Goodloe, J.W.,1968 (Box AC-14)
    - Grabarek, R.W.,1963and1965 (Box AC-14)
    - Graham, Billy,1962 (Box AC-14)
    - Graham, Frank P.,1949 (Box AC-14)
    - Grolier Society,1937and1939 (Box AC-14)
    - G,1957-1983, 6 folders (Box AC-14)
    - Haiti,1956and1968 (Box AC-15)
    - Halleck, Charles A.,1960 (Box AC-15)
    - Harriman, W. Averell,1963 (Box AC-15)
    - Harris, Rencher N.,1957-1964 (Box AC-15)
    - Hays, Brooks,1957-1969 (Box AC-15)
    - Helms, Jesse,1965-1982 (Box AC-15)
    - Hemmingway, Mary,1965 (Box AC-15)
    - Herald-Sun Papers,1937-1942 (Box AC-15)
    - Herter, Christian A.,1957-1960 (Box AC-15)
    - Hodges, Luther,1954-1967 (Box AC-15)
    - Hoey, Clyde R.,1953 (Box AC-15)
    - Holcomb, Luther,1965-1970 (Box AC-15)
    - Holland Furnace Company,1936-1943 (Box AC-15)
    - Holshouser, James B., Jr.,1972-1973 (Box AC-15)
    - Hospital Care Association,1939and1944 (Box AC-15)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H.,1966-1968 (Box AC-15)
    - Hunt, James B.,1970-1982 (Box AC-15)
    - H,1953-1982, Folders 1-7 of 11 (Box AC-16)
    - H,1953-1982, Folders 8-11 of 11 (Box AC-17)
    - Itineraries,1962-1965 (Box AC-17)
    - Ives, Irving M.,1957 (Box AC-17)
    - I,1957-1969 (Box AC-17)
    - Jackson, Maynard H., Jr.,1969 (Box AC-18)
    - Jain, Lakshmi C.,1959 (Box AC-18)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B.,1958-1969, 3 folders (Box AC-18)
    - Johnson Publishing Company,1950-1969 (Box AC-18)
    - Jonas, Charles Raper,1954-1971 (Box AC-18)
    - Jones, Norman E. (Agency),1967 (Box AC-18)
    - Jones, Thomas T.,1958-1972 (Box AC-18)
    - Jordan, B. Everett,1960-1971 (Box AC-18)
    - Junior Chamber of Commerce,1969 (Box AC-18)
    - J,1956-1978, 8 folders (Box AC-19)
    - Kennedy, Edward M.,1964 (Box AC-20)
    - Kennedy, John F. (Administration),1960-1963 (Box AC-20)
    - Kennedy, W.J., Jr.,1934-1967 (Box AC-20)
    - Kennedy, W.J., III,1959 (Box AC-20)
    - Knight, Douglas M.,1963-1971 (Box AC-20)
    - Knowland, William F.,1957 (Box AC-20)
    - Kornegay, Horace R.,1961-1967 (Box AC-20)
    - K,1959-1969, 5 folders (Box AC-20)
    - L. and C. Mayers Company,1935-1942 (Box AC-21)
    - Lanier, Edwin S.,1962-1965 (Box AC-21)
    - Lee, W. Cartwright,1934-1939 (Box AC-21)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot,1960 (Box AC-21)
    - Lennon, Allen,1953-1954 (Box AC-21)
    - Loveland Groves, Inc.,1967 (Box AC-21)
    - Lynch, Lorenzo,1971 (Box AC-21)
    - L,1953-1982, Folders 1-4 of 6 (Box AC-21)
    - L,1953-1982, Folders 5-6 of 6 (Box AC-22)
    - Maafo, Eugene Victor Amkye,1960-1964 (Box AC-22)
    - McCarthy, Eugene J.,1964 (Box AC-22)
    - Marshall, Thurgood,1961-1969 (Box AC-22)
    - Marvin, Murray J.,1962-1969 (Box AC-22)
    - Mays, Benjamin E.,1957-1970 (Box AC-22)
    - Merger (Durham Schools),1971 (Box AC-22)
    - Meyer's Department Store,1939 (Box AC-22)
    - Michaux, H.M. "Mickey,"1963-1982 (Box AC-22)
    - Mitchell, James P.,1957 (Box AC-22)
    - Moore, Daniel E.,1942-1945 (Box AC-22)
    - Moore, Daniel K.,1964-1969 (Box AC-22)
    - Morris, Calvin S.,1970 (Box AC-22)
    - Morrow, E. Frederic,1955-1962 (Box AC-22)
    - M,1957-1980, Folder 1 of 9 (Box AC-22)
    - M,1957-1980, Folders 2-6 of 9 (Box AC-23)
    - M,1957-1980, Folders 7-9 of 9 (Box AC-24)
    - Nasbit, James N.,1959-1965 (Box AC-24)
    - NASA,1969 (Box AC-24)
    - National Catholic Conference for International Justice,1969 (Box AC-24)
    - National Council of Jewish Women,1970 (Box AC-24)
    - Nigerian Correspondents,1965-1971 (Box AC-24)
    - Nixon, Richard M.,1956-1971 (Box AC-24)
    - N,1936-1983, 3 folders (Box AC-25)
    - O,1941-1980 (Box AC-25)
    - Pace, Frank,1964and1970 (Box AC-26)
    - Pageant Magazine, 1963and1965 (Box AC-26)
    - Paschall Brothers,1936-1946 (Box AC-26)
    - Percy, Charles H.,1967 (Box AC-26)
    - Pittsburgh Courier, 1938-1963 (Box AC-26)
    - Poitier, Sidney,1973 (Box AC-26)
    - Polish Correspondents,1960-1966, 4 folders (Box AC-26)
    - Postal Rate Increase,1962 (Box AC-26)
    - Powell, Adam Clayton,1958and1969 (Box AC-26)
    - Powell, C.B.,1943-1946 (Box AC-26)
    - Pullman Company,1939-1954 (Box AC-26)
    - P,1937-1981, Folder 1 of 7 (Box AC-26)
    - P,1937-1981, Folders 2-7 of 7 (Box AC-27)
    - Q,1939-1971 (Box AC-27)
    - Rabb, Maxwell M.,1958-1971 (Box AC-28)
    - Reader's Digest, 1958and1971 (Box AC-28)
    - Retired Field Employees,1962 (Box AC-28)
    - Retirement,1967 Apr.-Nov., 3 folders (Box AC-28)
    - Rusk, Dean,1960-1965 (Box AC-28)
    - Richardson, Scovel,1964and1969 (Box AC-28)
    - Robinson, Jackie,1962 (Box AC-28)
    - Rockefeller, David,1971 (Box AC-28)
    - Rockefeller, John D.,1963-1964 (Box AC-28)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A.,1958-1963 (Box AC-28)
    - Rockefeller, Rodman C.,1967and1970 (Box AC-28)
    - Rockefeller, Winthrop,1953and1963 (Box AC-28)
    - Rogers, William P.,1957 (Box AC-28)
    - Romney, George,1962 (Box AC-28)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., Jr.,1964-1965 (Box AC-28)
    - R,1933-1983, Folders 1-3 of 7 (Box AC-28)
    - R,1933-1983, Folders 4-7 of 7 (Box AC-29)
    - Sampson, Edith S.,1969 (Box AC-29)
    - Sanford, Terry,1960-1971 (Box AC-29)
    - Scott, Hugh,1957-1971 (Box AC-29)
    - Scott, Robert W.,1960-1971 (Box AC-29)
    - Scott, W. Kerr (Box AC-29)
    - Scranton, William W.,1962 (Box AC-29)
    - Sears Roebuck and Company,1936 (Box AC-29)
    - Seaton, Fred A.,1960 (Box AC-29)
    - Secretary of the Navy,1969 (Box AC-29)
    - Shell Oil Company,1937and1941 (Box AC-29)
    - Shepard, James E., Dr. (Box AC-29)
    - Smith, J.E.,1964 (Box AC-29)
    - Smith, McNeill,1973 (Box AC-29)
    - Some American Profiles in an Age of Challenge, 1960 (Box AC-29)
    - Speaker Services for United Nations,1960-1964 (Box AC-30)
    - Speaking Engagements (Wilmington, NC),1964 (Box AC-30)
    - Speaking Engagements,1957, 1959-1960, 1962, 4 folders (Box AC-30)
    - Staley, Ed,1967-1972 (Box AC-30)
    - Stevenson, Adlai E.,1960and1963 (Box AC-30)
    - Sullivan, Leon H.,1970 (Box AC-30)
    - Sullivan, William C.,1963-1967 (Box AC-30)
    - Summit Meeting of National Negro Leaders,1958 (Box AC-30)
    - S,1937-1983, Folder 1 of 11 (Box AC-30)
    - S,1937-1983, Folders 2-5 of 11 (Box AC-31)
    - S,1937-1983, Folders 6-10 of 11 (Box AC-32)
    - S,1937-1983, Folder 11 of 11 (Box AC-33)
    - Telegrams,1944-1970 (Box AC-33)
    - Telephones, undated (Box AC-33)
    - Thank You Messages,1958-1962 (Box AC-33)
    - Hotel Theresa,1941-1946 (Box AC-33)
    - Thomas, Norman,1965 (Box AC-33)
    - Travel Guides, undated (Box AC-33)
    - Trowbridge, Alexander B.,1967 (Box AC-33)
    - Truman, Harry S,1945 (Box AC-33)
    - Turpin, C. Udell,1948-1969 (Box AC-33)
    - Two Thousand Men of Achievement,1971 (Box AC-33)
    - T,1936-1983, Folder 1 of 4 (Box AC-33)
    - T,1936-1983, Folders 2-4 of 4 (Box AC-34)
    - Umstead, William B.,1937and1952 (Box AC-34)
    - United Business Committee of the National Association of Manufactures,1962 (Box AC-34)
    - United Mutual Life Insurance Company,1960-1961 (Box AC-34)
    - United States. Department of Commerce,1966 (Box AC-34)
    - United States. Department of Justice,1979 (Box AC-35)
    - United States. Trade Development Mission to Central America and Panama,1963-1964 (Box AC-35)
    - University of Michigan,1966-1974 (Box AC-35)
    - Unknown correspondents, undated (Box AC-35)
    - U,1939-1969 (Box AC-35)
    - V,1945-1969 (Box AC-36)
    - WABC Radio Station, undated (Box AC-36)
    - Wallace, Henry A.,1945 (Box AC-36)
    - Washington, Val J.,1948-1971, 4 folders (Box AC-36)
    - Weaver, Robert C.,1962-1967 (Box AC-36)
    - Welsh, Matthew E.,1963 (Box AC-36)
    - Weltner, Charles Longstreet,1965 (Box AC-36)
    - White, W. Wilson,1958 (Box AC-36)
    - Willkie, Wendell L.,1942 (Box AC-36)
    - Woman's Day Magazine, 1967 (Box AC-36)
    - Women's Wear Daily, 1967 (Box AC-36)
    - World War II,1942 (Box AC-36)
    - W,1936-1973, Folders 1-4 of 8 (Box AC-37)
    - W,1936-1973, Folders 5-8 of 8 (Box AC-38)
    - YMCA,1937-1942 (Box AC-38)
    - Young, Andrew,1976-1978 (Box AC-38)
    - Y,1944-1967 (Box AC-38)
    - Z,1956-1970 (Box AC-38)
  - Writings and Speeches Series, 1931-1981, bulk late 1950s-late 1970s, 17 boxes
    Addresses, articles, opinion columns, press releases, speeches, diaries, and other writings. Works that exist in multiple drafts are so noted in the list. A large amount of writing, interviews, notes, and research for Spaulding's uncompleted autobiography is filed under the assigned title, "Autobiography." See the Subject Files Series for additional biographical information about Spaulding and his family. The bulk of the series, writings by Spaulding, is arranged alphabetically by title. Miscellaneous writings by others are filed alphabetically by surname at the end of the series under "Works by Other Authors."
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Use of unpublished interviews in autobiographical material is restricted. Permission is not granted for publication. The user is responsible for obtaining permission to publish from the interviews.
    - Acceptance of Interracial Council for Business Opportunity First Business Achievement Award, 1964 Dec. 3 (Box AWS-1)
    - Action is The Word and related correspondence. Address to the Eighteenth National Alumni Conference of theTuskeegee Institute Alumni Association of New York, 1967 Aug. 12, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-1)
    - Actuarial Profession as a Career, for publication in his book Careers, and related correspondence, circa 1941-1942, 5 drafts (Box AWS-1)
    - Address to 18th Annual Sales Convention Banquet of North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1962 Feb. 21 (Box AWS-1)
    - Address of Asa T. Spaulding to the Students at the School of Business, U. N. C., 1964? (Box AWS-1)
    - Ambassador of Liberia to Washington to Visit Durham, circa 1979 (Box AWS-1)
    - America Loses a Friend and Anwar Sadat โ a Martyr for Peace!, 1981 Oct. (Box AWS-1)
    - Annual Statement, 63rd (NC Mutual), 1961 Dec. 31 (Box AWS-1)
    - The Annual Statement โ An Account of Stewardship, circa 1939 (Box AWS-1)
    - Anwar Sadat โ A Martyr for Peace, 1981 Oct. 6 (Box AWS-1)
    - An Appeal for the End of Violence and related correspondence, 1968 Apr. 9 (Box AWS-1)
    - Are We Being Kidded? for the New York Amsterdam Star News, 1942 Jan. 31 (Box AWS-1)
    - Are We Too Hard?, undated (Box AWS-1)
    - Are You a Murderer? or Respect for Human Life, undated (Box AWS-1)
    - Around the World with the Spauldings or '5000 Years in 56 Days' Parts 1-3,1957 (Box AWS-1)
    - At That Secret Place, undated (Box AWS-1)
    - An Autobiographical Presentation, Frederick Douglass Sesquicentennial Commemoration, University of Rochester, 1967 Mar. 16 (Box AWS-1)
    - An Autobiographical Presentation - notecards, 1967 Mar. 16 (Box AWS-1)
    - Autobiography
      - Correspondence, 1978 Jan.-1980, 4 folders (Box AWS-1)
    - Autobiography (Box AWS-2)
      - Correspondence,1981 Mar.-Oct., 2 folders (Box AWS-2)
      - Drafts
        - 1980 Table of Contents and related papers (Drafts from this Table of Contents to follow) (Box AWS-2)
        - 1981 Table of Contents and related papers (Drafts from this Table of Contents to follow this folder) (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapters 1-5, circa 1981, 5 folders (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapter 6, Section 1, circa 1981 (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapter 8, circa 1981 (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapter 3 1/2 and 1982 Table of Contents, circa 1982 (Box AWS-2)
        - Autobiography: Draft of 1983 Table of Contents (Drafts from this Table of Contents to follow) (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapter 1 โ multiple drafts, circa 1983 (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapters 2-5, circa 1983, 4 folders (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapter 6 โ multiple drafts, circa 1983 (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapter 6a (formerly 6b per 1983 Table of Contents), circa 1983 (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapter 6b (formerly 6c per 1983 Table of Contents), circa 1983 (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapter 6c (formerly 6a per 1983 Table of Contents), circa 1983 (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapter 7 โ multiple drafts, circa 1983 (Box AWS-2)
        - Chapters 8-9, circa 1983, 3 folders (Box AWS-2)
    - Autobiography (Box AWS-3)
      - Drafts
        - Chapters 9a-11, circa 1983, 3 folders (Box AWS-3)
        - Notes and Outlines, undated, 2 folders (Box AWS-3)
      - Interviews
        - Bean, Ambassador Maurice, 1979 Nov. 18 (Box AWS-3)
        - Berry, John L., 1979 Oct. 12 (Box AWS-3)
        - Bouleware, C. E. 1978 June (Box AWS-3)
        - Brennan, Mrs. Isadora, 1979 Apr. 4 (Box AWS-3)
        - Bryant, R. Kelly Jr., 1979 Mar. 1 (Box AWS-3)
        - Burns, William, 1979 June 27 (Box AWS-3)
        - Butler, Mr. E. M., 1979 Apr. 6 (Box AWS-3)
        - Campbell, Dr., 1979 June 28 (Box AWS-3)
        - Campbell, Dr. J. E. (summary), 1979 June (Box AWS-3)
        - Carterette, Miss Clara, 1979 Apr. 5 (Box AWS-3)
        - Clement, W. A., 1979 Apr. 4 (Box AWS-3)
        - Dowdy, Dr. Lewis, 1979 June 25 (Box AWS-3)
        - Edmunds, Dr. Helen, 1979 Apr. 2 (Box AWS-3)
        - Gregg, N. L., 1979 June 25 (Box AWS-3)
        - Henderson, J. J., 1979 Apr. 2 (Box AWS-3)
        - Jones, Dorsie [Dossie?], 1979 Mar. 1 (Box AWS-3)
        - Kennedy, W. J., Jr., 1979 June 27 (Box AWS-3)
        - Kennedy, W. J., III, 1979 Mar. 1, 2 folders (Box AWS-3)
        - Lynch, Rev. Lorenzo, 1979 Apr. 2 (Box AWS-3)
        - Nichols, Dr. Owen B., 1979 Oct. 11 (Box AWS-3)
        - Rollins, Steed, 1979 June 28 (Box AWS-3)
        - Rollins, Steed (summary), 1979 June 28 (Box AWS-3)
        - Sansom, James Jr., 1979 June 28 (Box AWS-3)
        - Scarborough, Dewey S., 1979 June 27 (Box AWS-3)
        - Spaulding, Asa T.,1979 (Box AWS-3)
        - Spaulding, John Andrew, 1979 Mar. 29 (Box AWS-3)
        - Spears, A. E., 1979 June 22 (Box AWS-3)
        - Swindell, Edward, 1979 June 27 (Box AWS-3)
        - Watts, Dr. C. D., 1979 Apr. 3 (Box AWS-3)
    - Autobiography (Box AWS-4)
      - Interviews
        - White, N. B., 1979 Apr. 4 (Box AWS-4)
        - Williams, Dr. Lorraine, 1979 Sept. 26 (Box AWS-4)
        - Woods, Dr. Geraldine, 1979 Sept. 19 (Box AWS-4)
        - Wyche, Mr. Henry, 1979 Apr. 5 (Box AWS-4)
        - Permission request and restriction forms (drafts of sample forms used by Spaulding) (Box AWS-4)
        - Questionnaires completed by persons providing info on A. T. Spaulding for the Autobiography (form by John Fleming) (Box AWS-4)
        - Resume of John Fleming, conductor of interviews, and related papers, circa 1979 Jan. (Box AWS-4)
      - Proposal,1978 (Box AWS-4)
      - Research Material
        - General Research Material, 3 folders (Box AWS-4)
          See also "Biographical" folders in Subject Files.
        - Biographical Sketches,1960-1981 (Box AWS-4)
        - Family, circa 1980 (Box AWS-4)
        - Family Reunion,1981, 2 folders (Box AWS-4)
    - Autobiography (Box AWS-5)
      - Research Materials
        - FBI Investigation,1979 (Box AWS-5)
        - North Carolina Mutual, 1935-1968 and undated (Box AWS-5)
      - Autobiography: Titles (Spaulding's notes), undated (Box AWS-5)
    - Backstage North Carolina Mutual, N.C. Mutual Managers' Advisory Council Meeting,1953 May 28, 3 copies (Box AWS-5)
    - Baptist Fish, undated (Box AWS-5)
    - Beginning of the Shaw University Speakers Forum, undated, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-5)
    - Behavioral Science and Company Social Responsibility โ Two of the Many Concerns of Present Day Management, address before University of North Carolina School of Business Administration Chapter of Beta Gamma Sigma National Honor Society, 1964 May 7, 2 drafts (Box AWS-5)
    - Black Business in the New South, undated (Box AWS-5)
    - Bloody Sunday, undated (Box AWS-5)
    - The Bridge to the Other Side, 1965 (Box AWS-5)
    - Bridging Gaps, undated (Box AWS-5)
    - A Brief History of the Civil Rights Movement since 1900, 1969 Nov. 14, 2 copies (Box AWS-5)
    - A Brief Outline History of the Organization, Growth, and Development of the North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Co., 1898-1931, circa 1931 (Box AWS-5)
    - The Business of Voluntary Support and related correspondence,1967 (Box AWS-5)
    - A Challenge of the Ages: A 1978 Crusade for Peace! and related work, 1977 Dec., Multiple drafts (Box AWS-5)
    - Challenge an Opportunity and Opportunity a Challenge โ A Commencement Address at Durham Business College, 1962 June 2 (Box AWS-5)
    - Challenge โ Response and Change, Keynote Address: Business Clinic and Founder's Day and related correspondence, 1962 Apr. 9 and 1963 Apr. 28, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-5)
    - Change, By Evolution or Revolution, circa 1979, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-5)
    - Change Made, Change Still Needed, opinion column,Durham Sun, 1979 May 25 (Box AWS-5)
    - Charting Our Course for the Future, 1938 June 16, 2 copies (Box AWS-5)
    - Christmas Prayer from the President, undated (Box AWS-5)
    - Citizen Views: Appeal for Unity, 1979 May 7 (Box AWS-5)
    - Climate, undated (Box AWS-6)
    - A Collection of Some Sayings By Asa T. Spaulding, Sr. โ unpublished, 1973 Feb. 12 (Box AWS-6)
    - Columbus County, undated (Box AWS-6)
    - Commencement Address, Graduating Class Matthew's County Junior High School, circa 1935 (Box AWS-6)
    - Concept โ Let's Not Violate It, undated (Box AWS-6)
    - Concerning the statement made by Asa Spaulding at the National Urban League Conference, 1963 Aug. (Box AWS-6)
    - Corporate Policy, undated (Box AWS-6)
    - Crises โ History Making Opportunites, undated (Box AWS-6)
    - The Crusader, undated (Box AWS-6)
    - A Day for Great Ideas โ A Challenge to College Students, undated (Box AWS-6)
    - Dedication-- Keynote address Dr. Andrew F. Brimmer member Federal Reserve Board of Governors, circa 1966 (Box AWS-6)
    - Delivery By a Day Pregnant with History, circa 1969 (Box AWS-6)
    - Diaries (travel diaries),1955-1956, 1964-1969, Folders 1-3 of 4 (Box AWS-6)
    - Diaries (travel diaries),1955-1956, 1964-1969, Folder 4 of 4 (Box AWS-7)
    - Discrimination and the Negro in the United States at the 9th General Conference of UNESCO and related correspondence, 1956 Nov. 26 (Box AWS-7)
    - Discrimination Immoral and Costly, undated (Box AWS-7)
    - Do You Want to Get Well? Do You Want to Be a Successful Staff Man?, undated (Box AWS-7)
    - Dr. A. M. Moore and North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1966 Oct. 20, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-7)
    - Dr. Helen G. Edmonds Makes Impact Upon the Durham Community, 1977 May 7, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-7)
    - Duke Homestead Ceremonies, 1968 Apr. 28, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-7)
    - The Durham of Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow and related correspondence, Downtown Development Association Annual Meeting,1963 Aug. 28, 2 drafts (Box AWS-7)
    - Durham Pays Tribute to Sergeant Joe Louis Barrow, 1944 (Box AWS-7)
    - Durham's Greatest Need! letter to the editor,Durham Sun, 1979 Apr. 22 (Box AWS-7)
    - Effective Employer-Employee Relations in the Small Business and related correspondence, 1963 May, 2 copies (Box AWS-7)
    - Election is step-by-step process, 1980 Aug. 22 (Box AWS-7)
    - Emancipation Greetings, 1966 Jan. 1 (Box AWS-7)
    - Emotions of the Soul: What Hath God Wrought, 1977 Nov. 21 (Box AWS-7)
    - Equal Employment Opportunity from the Viewpoint of a Negro Employer, delivered as panelist at "Equal Employment Opportunity Luncheon," Chamber of Commerce of the United States Fifty-Third Annual Meeting,1965 Apr. 26 (Box AWS-7)
    - Facing the Future with What Foundations! report to the Officers and Directors, NC Mutual Life Insurance Company,1939 Jan. 9 (Box AWS-7)
    - Fiftieth Anniversary Program, 1949 Apr. 1 (Box AWS-7)
    - 5000 Years in 50 Days, 1956 Nov.-Dec. (Box AWS-7)
    - Flying from Bermuda to Philadelphia, 1980 Feb. 10 (Box AWS-7)
    - Focus on the Future โ UNESCO at New Delhi, 1956, 1956 (Box AWS-7)
    - For Life โ On What Foundations? circa 1937, 4 drafts and 1 page of a partial draft (Box AWS-7)
    - For a United Durham, 1951 May (Box AWS-7)
    - From the President's Desk (Series; individual titles follow)
      - A Burning Issue, 1963 (Box AWS-7)
      - Corporate Social Responsibility, circa 1966 (Box AWS-7)
      - Education and Freedom in a World of Conflict, 1961 Apr., 3 drafts (Box AWS-7)
      - For The Whetstone educational issue,1959 June, 3 drafts (Box AWS-7)
      - For The Whetstone life underwriter's issue, undated, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-7)
      - The Jesus Way, undated (Box AWS-7)
      - Life Insurance in an Exploding Economy, circa 1959 (Box AWS-7)
      - More and Better Education a Necessity, undated (Box AWS-7)
      - More and Better Education Needed, undated (Box AWS-7)
      - North Carolina Mutual's 57th Anniversary Celebration, 1956 (Box AWS-7)
      - Preparation for the Abundant Life, 1967 (Box AWS-7)
      - Report to Policyholders, 1963 (Box AWS-7)
      - What it Takes to Excel as a Life Underwriter, 1966 (Box AWS-7)
      - What We Dedicated, circa 1966 (Box AWS-7)
      - Untitled, undated, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-7)
    - Ghanaian Council Encourages U. S. Private Investment, International Commerce, 1967 Apr. 10 (Box AWS-7)
    - A Giant Oak Has Fallen! (regarding death of Pres. Emeritus of Howard University, Dr. Mordecai Wyatt Johnson),1976, 2 drafts (Box AWS-7)
    - The Good Samaritan; the Golden Rule โ Christmas (Whetstone article for Christmas), undated (Box AWS-7)
    - Good Tidings of Great Joy โ For Whom? and Where are the Nine? undated, 2 drafts (Box AWS-7)
    - Half a Billion Insurance, 1944 Mar. (Box AWS-8)
    - A Historic Social Function, 1959 Nov. (Box AWS-8)
    - The History of Negro Insurance in the United States, 1943 Aug. 31 (Box AWS-8)
    - If a Man Can.. .Build a Better Mouse Trap, 1966 June 6 (Box AWS-8)
    - If I Were a High School Student Today, 1963 Sept. (Box AWS-8)
    - Immediate Problems Facing Our Companies: Specific Agency Expense, 1937 May 27 (Box AWS-8)
    - The Impact of the Changing World on Women's Organizations โ Economically: An Overall Picture of the Economic Situation as It Relates to the Negro People, address at theNational Council of Negro Women, Inc. Conference, 1956 May 26, Typescripts and multiple printings (Box AWS-8)
    - The Importance of One's Choices and Performances in Career Building, delivered at Howard University School of Business and Public Administration, 1978 Oct. 19 (Box AWS-8)
    - Impressions from Twenty Days Behind the 'Iron Curtain,' 1969, 1970, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-8)
    - India and Its People, 1957 (Box AWS-8)
    - India and UNESCO, 1957 July 27, 2 drafts (Box AWS-8)
    - 'In the Fullness of Time;' A Crusade for Peace! A 1978 New Year's Challenge! 1978, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-8)